<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Classes on Visual Analytics</title>
    <link>/class/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Classes on Visual Analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/class/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Amounts</title>
      <link>/class/04-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class/04-class/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Slides US birth data Clearest and muddiest things   Slides Download the slides from today’s lecture.
   US birth data Here’s the data I used:
  Data from the CDC and SSA (via FiveThirtyEight)  Here’s a more complete version of the code I wrote in class:
  birth-plots.Rmd  The complete RStudio project  The knitted birth-plots.html  Clearest and muddiest things Go to this form and answer these two questions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Representation Basics II</title>
      <link>/class/03-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class/03-class/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Slides Extra-dimensional aesthetics Guessing the identity of the Trump resistance op-ed writer with R Workhouses and star movies Clearest and muddiest things   Slides Download the slides from today’s lecture.
   Extra-dimensional aesthetics  Make your own animated plots with gganimate Video of simulated Hurricane Florence storm surge The Wall Street Journal’s audio-based visualization of Hamilton’s internal rhymes  Guessing the identity of the Trump resistance op-ed writer with R  David Robinson’s approach Mike Kearney’s approach: his code and his short article  Workhouses and star movies Download this zip file, extract it, and open the file named week3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Representation Basics I</title>
      <link>/class/02-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class/02-class/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Slides Quick redesign Clearest and muddiest things   Slides Download the slides from today’s lecture.
   Quick redesign Choose one of these on-campus fliers and redesign it in a small group:
 BYU Student Wellness:  All assets Safe Kids Utah County:  All assets  Clearest and muddiest things Go to this form and answer these two questions:
What was the muddiest thing from class today?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Visual Analytics</title>
      <link>/class/01-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/class/01-class/</guid>
      <description>Contents  Slides Playing with LEGO Clearest and muddiest things   Slides Download the slides from today’s lecture.
   Playing with LEGO The R Markdown file we (briefly) played with is here.
Clearest and muddiest things Go to this form and answer these two questions:
What was the muddiest thing from class today? What are you still wondering about? What was the clearest thing from class today? What was the most exciting thing you learned?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>