<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Readings on Visual Analytics</title>
    <link>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Readings on Visual Analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Representation Basics II</title>
      <link>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/03-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/03-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required   Hans Rosling, “200 Countries, 200 Years, 4 Minutes”  Chapter 2 in Claus Wilke, Fundamentals of Data VisualizationClaus E. Wilke, Fundamentals of Data Visualization (Sebastopol, California: O’Reilly Media, 2018), https://serialmentor.com/dataviz/.
  Chapter 3 in Kieran Healy, Data VisualizationKieran Healy, Data Visualization: A Practical Introduction (Princeton: Princeton University Press, 2018), http://socviz.co/.
  Recommended Walking through this chapter here and working through all the code will be immensely helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Representation Basics I</title>
      <link>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/02-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/02-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required   Chapter 4 and Chapter 22 in Claus Wilke, Fundamentals of Data VisualizationClaus E. Wilke, Fundamentals of Data Visualization (Sebastopol, California: O’Reilly Media, 2018), https://serialmentor.com/dataviz/.
  Questions to reflect on  Questions TBD  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Visual Analytics</title>
      <link>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/01-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/01-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required Given this is the first class, there are no required readings.
Questions to reflect on  How do we know what is true? Are facts truth? Why do we visualize data? What makes a great visualization? How do you choose which kind of visualization to use?  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Truth, beauty, and data revisited</title>
      <link>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/14-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/14-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required   Chapter 12 in Alberto Cairo, The Truthful ArtAlberto Cairo, The Truthful Art: Data, Charts, and Maps for Communication (Berkeley, California: New Riders, 2016).
  Chapter 24 in Claus Wilke, Fundamentals of Data VisualizationClaus E. Wilke, Fundamentals of Data Visualization (Sebastopol, California: O’Reilly Media, 2018), https://serialmentor.com/dataviz/.
  Ben Wellington, “Making data mean more through storytelling”  Jonathan Schwabish, “Better Data Communication,” National Bureau of Economic Research  Why People Make Bad Charts (and What to Do When it Happens)  Questions to reflect on  Questions TBD  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing graphics</title>
      <link>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/13-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/13-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required   Chapter 15, Chapter 16, Chapter 18, Chapter 20, and Chapter 21 in Claus Wilke, Fundamentals of Data VisualizationClaus E. Wilke, Fundamentals of Data Visualization (Sebastopol, California: O’Reilly Media, 2018), https://serialmentor.com/dataviz/.
  Chapter 8 in Kieran Healy, Data VisualizationKieran Healy, Data Visualization: A Practical Introduction (Princeton: Princeton University Press, 2018), http://socviz.co/.
 Other readings TBD  Questions to reflect on  Questions TBD  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annotating and grouping</title>
      <link>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/12-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/12-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required   Chapter 17 and Chapter 19 in Claus Wilke, Fundamentals of Data VisualizationClaus E. Wilke, Fundamentals of Data Visualization (Sebastopol, California: O’Reilly Media, 2018), https://serialmentor.com/dataviz/.
  Chapter 5 in Kieran Healy, Data VisualizationKieran Healy, Data Visualization: A Practical Introduction (Princeton: Princeton University Press, 2018), http://socviz.co/.
 Other readings TBD  Questions to reflect on  Questions TBD  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text</title>
      <link>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/11-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/11-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required   Look through some of the chapters in Julia Silge and David Robinson, Tidy Text MiningJulia Silge and David Robinson, Text Mining with R (Sebastopol, California: O’Reilly Media, 2017), https://www.tidytextmining.com/.
 (but definitely don’t read them all! You just need to get a taste of what modern text analysis looks like.) A bunch of (really) short things:   Julia Silge, “She Giggles, He Gallops”  Abby Ohlheiser, “These are the words most associated with men and women, according to Facebook status updates”  Six Ideas for Displaying Qualitative Data  Word clouds considered harmful  Word clouds cause death… or something  When It’s Ok to Use Word Clouds  The Class of 2011  Every time Ford and Kavanaugh dodged a question, in one chart  Sentiment Analysis of The Book of Mormon  Tweet by @s_soroka   Questions to reflect on  Why is qualitative data difficult to visualize?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Space</title>
      <link>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/10-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/10-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required   Chapter 10 in Alberto Cairo, The Truthful ArtAlberto Cairo, The Truthful Art: Data, Charts, and Maps for Communication (Berkeley, California: New Riders, 2016).
  Chapter 7 in Kieran Healy, Data VisualizationKieran Healy, Data Visualization: A Practical Introduction (Princeton: Princeton University Press, 2018), http://socviz.co/.
  It looks like this is a lot of reading, but lots of these are short videos or tweets or interactive websites, so don’t worry!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time</title>
      <link>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/09-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/09-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required   Chapter 8 in Alberto Cairo, The Truthful ArtAlberto Cairo, The Truthful Art: Data, Charts, and Maps for Communication (Berkeley, California: New Riders, 2016).
  The Nuclear Threat—The Shadow Peace, part 1  11 Ways to Visualize Changes Over Time – A Guide A bunch of (really) short blog posts:   Streamgraphs: Economic trade flows with R  A century of ocean shipping animated  What is seasonal adjustment and why is it used?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparisons</title>
      <link>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/08-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/08-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required   Chapter 9 in Claus Wilke, Fundamentals of Data VisualizationClaus E. Wilke, Fundamentals of Data Visualization (Sebastopol, California: O’Reilly Media, 2018), https://serialmentor.com/dataviz/.
  Sparkline theory and practiceThis is a collection of posts by Edward Tufte about sparklines—scroll down a ways and check out his examples, analysis, and critiques.
  Time series sparklines  The bullet graph  Lollipop chartsIf you’re feeling adventurous (and you should!), do this tutorial as you read it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relationships</title>
      <link>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/07-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/07-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required   Chapter 9 in Alberto Cairo, The Truthful ArtAlberto Cairo, The Truthful Art: Data, Charts, and Maps for Communication (Berkeley, California: New Riders, 2016).
  Chapter 12 in Claus Wilke, Fundamentals of Data VisualizationClaus E. Wilke, Fundamentals of Data Visualization (Sebastopol, California: O’Reilly Media, 2018), https://serialmentor.com/dataviz/.
  Kieran Healy, “Two y-axes”  Two Alternatives to Using a Second Y-Axis &amp;amp; Illusion of success &amp;amp; Dissecting two axes  Dual-Scaled Axes in Graphs: Are They Ever the Best Solution?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncertainty</title>
      <link>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/06-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/06-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required   Chapter 7 in Claus Wilke, Fundamentals of Data VisualizationClaus E. Wilke, Fundamentals of Data Visualization (Sebastopol, California: O’Reilly Media, 2018), https://serialmentor.com/dataviz/.
  Chapters 4, 7, and 11 in Alberto Cairo, The Truthful ArtAlberto Cairo, The Truthful Art: Data, Charts, and Maps for Communication (Berkeley, California: New Riders, 2016).
  Why It’s So Hard for Us to Visualize Uncertainty  Amanda Cox’s keynote address at the 2017 OpenVis Conf  Communicating Uncertainty When Lives Are on the Line  Showing uncertainty during the live election forecast &amp;amp; Trolling the uncertainty dial  Questions to reflect on  Why is it important to deal with uncertainty in data?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proportions</title>
      <link>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/05-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/05-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required   Chapter 10 in Claus Wilke, Fundamentals of Data VisualizationClaus E. Wilke, Fundamentals of Data Visualization (Sebastopol, California: O’Reilly Media, 2018), https://serialmentor.com/dataviz/.
  Engaging Readers with Square Pie/Waffle Charts  Understanding Pie Charts&amp;#8853;Figure 2 from Ivelina Momcheva and Erik Tollerud, “Software Use in Astronomy: An Informal Survey,” July 14, 2015, https://arxiv.org/abs/1507.03989.
  Square pie chart beats out the rest in perception study  Recommended   Ian Spence, “No Humble Pie: The Origins and Usage of a Statistical Chart”Ian Spence, “No Humble Pie: The Origins and Usage of a Statistical Chart,” Journal of Educational and Behavioral Statistics 30, nos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amounts</title>
      <link>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/04-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dsba5122-spring2019.netlify.com/reading/04-reading/</guid>
      <description>Required   Chapter 6 in Claus Wilke, Fundamentals of Data VisualizationClaus E. Wilke, Fundamentals of Data Visualization (Sebastopol, California: O’Reilly Media, 2018), https://serialmentor.com/dataviz/.
  Chapter 6 in Alberto Cairo, The Truthful ArtAlberto Cairo, The Truthful Art: Data, Charts, and Maps for Communication (Berkeley, California: New Riders, 2016).
  Questions to reflect on  How do these types of visualizations help or hinder or search for truth in data?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>